<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog posts | OSCAR</title><link>https://oscar-project.org/post/</link><atom:link href="https://oscar-project.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Blog posts</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><image><url>https://oscar-project.org/media/sharing.png</url><title>Blog posts</title><link>https://oscar-project.org/post/</link></image><item><title>News: OSCAR 23.01 Release</title><link>https://oscar-project.org/post/news-23-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 15:02:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://oscar-project.org/post/news-23-01/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert alert-note">
&lt;div>
The new OSCAR 23.01 is finally available, check it out &lt;a href="https://oscar-project.github.io/documentation/versions/oscar-2301/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>! ðŸš€
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>After one year of work, we&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce the release of OSCAR 23.01! ðŸš€ OSCAR 23.01 is the January 2023 version of the OSCAR Corpus based on the &lt;a href="https://commoncrawl.org/2022/12/nov-dec-2022-crawl-archive-now-available/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">November/December 2022 dump of Common Crawl&lt;/a>. While being quite similar to OSCAR 22.01, it contains several new features, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://kheafield.com/code/kenlm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">KenLM&lt;/a>-based adult content detection ðŸ‘€&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Precomputed &lt;a href="https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Locality_sensitive_hashing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Locality-Sensitive Hashes&lt;/a> for near deduplication ðŸ“&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://dsi.ut-capitole.fr/blacklists/index_en.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blocklist&lt;/a>-based categories ðŸ“š&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://facebook.github.io/zstd/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zstandard compression&lt;/a> ðŸ“¦&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A new blocklist specifically made for Japanese ðŸ‡¯ðŸ‡µ&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Language naming changes to better respect the BCP47 standard âœï¸ðŸ¤“&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To get access to this version and more information about it, please visit our documentation &lt;a href="https://oscar-project.github.io/documentation/versions/oscar-2301/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OSCAR News: September 2021</title><link>https://oscar-project.org/post/news-21-09/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 15:45:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://oscar-project.org/post/news-21-09/</guid><description>&lt;p>September 2021 marks an important milestone regarding OSCAR, and we have important news to share.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="new-pipeline-tool">New pipeline tool&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="../oscar-2019">previous&lt;/a> OSCAR corpus was generated by &lt;a href="https://github.com/oscar-corpus/goclassy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">goclassy&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The &lt;a href="../oscar-v21-09">latest&lt;/a> (at the time of writing) and future ones will be generated by &lt;a href="https://github.com/oscar-corpus/Ungoliant" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ungoliant&lt;/a>, a brand new corpus generation tool written in &lt;a href="https://rust-lang.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rust&lt;/a>.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The tool provides a more accessible Command Line Interface, with the following features:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dowloading of CommonCrawl shards from a &lt;code>wet.paths&lt;/code> file,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Generation of a corpus from CommonCrawl shards,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deduplication,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Splitting in files of fixed maxiumum size,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Packaging (GZipping + checksum file creation)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>It is also possible (but not yet used/tested in terms of ergonomics) to use Ungoliant as a library.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="new-schema">New schema&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>OSCAR is changing and will change again on the course of the following months/years, and as such it is important to provide a way to announce and specify schema changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new OSCAR Corpus release follows the OSCAR Schema v1.1, enabling users to optionally get metadata extracted from CommonCrawl, while retaining backward compatibility, making the update from OSCAR 2018 to OSCAR 21.09 as effortless as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a gist, OSCAR Schema v1.1 adds &lt;code>&amp;lt;lang&amp;gt;_meta.jsonl&lt;/code> &lt;a href="https://jsonlines.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">JSONLines&lt;/a> files that holds metadata. Each line has an &lt;code>offset&lt;/code> and an &lt;code>nb_sentences&lt;/code> field that can be used to get related lines in text files.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="new-corpus">New corpus&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>OSCAR 21.09 is the latest release of the OSCAR Corpus. The first to be generated by Ungoliant, and also the first containing metadata.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that the data used to generate the corpus is from February 2021, but the next releases of OSCAR Corpus will try to narrow the gap between source data and corpus release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another important information is that there is &lt;strong>no shuffled version anymore&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is expected to be available during September 2021 via manual application through the Contact form of the website, and later on other platforms.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>